[MIKASA] Everyone keeps saying
Eren has changed.
And I thought he had, too.
But...
I wonder if we've
all got it wrong.
[MIKASA]
It could be that he's always
been like this inside.
But if this is
the real Eren Jaeger...
...what did I see in him
that made me keep him so close?
Can you believe there are really
enough people outside the walls
to fill up such a gigantic city?
Try not to talk about the walls
in front of the
general public, Conny.
Ah, right. Sorry about that.
[SASHA] This is the world
beyond the walls.
We're finally here,
outside the walls
we've known our whole lives.
The walls no one
has ever escaped!
Gah, would you
listen to me for once?
If you think about it,
this is sort of
a return to the
Scouts' original mission.
[HANGE]
Let the survey begin.
Ahh.
[ONYANKOPON]
My friends!
I'd like to welcome you
to the continent of Marley!
The Azumabito have been waiting.
May I escort you?
Hey, Onyankopon!
[ONYANKOPON laughs] It's so good
to see you all here!
So, what does
everyone think about
the biggest port in the country?
[CONNY gasps]
What's with that horse?
Or, wait. Is that--
What was that?
Nah. No horse ever
looked like that.
I think it was a Marleyan cow!
[HANGE]
It must've been a car.
I've definitely
heard about those!
Hey! Car! Here, boy!
They're making a scene.
Everyone's staring!
[JEAN sighs] All these
people are gonna think
we're a bunch of yokels now.
[ARMIN gasps]
Just act like
you don't know him.
[HANGE] Come back, car!
I promise I'll be nice!
Better get them on a leash.
They'll try and
feed the car carrots
if they manage to catch it.
[ONYANKOPON laughs]
Give him more credit than tha--
Wait, are they buying carrots?
There are so many people here.
Stay near me, Eren.
We have no idea what to expect.
You're safest at my side.
You all right?
Yeah, got it.
[ARMIN] This is no time
to be spacing out, Eren!
We finally reached
the outside world!
We really made it
across the sea, huh?
We're here.
[LEVI]
Guys. Stick with the group.
Especially you, Eren.
Be right there!
[CIVILIAN 87A gasps]
Hey, watch where
you're walking, kid!
May I please have one?
But, of course!
[VENDOR 87A]
Here. Enjoy!
Whoa! Sasha!
Show some restraint!
[SASHA gasps]
How is it cold like that?
[CONNY]
I wanna try it!
I take it this is your
first time tasting ice cream!
What is this stuff made of?
I'd like one, too, please, sir!
[CONNY]
Me, too!
Those idiots. I told 'em
not to draw attention.
They stick out,
but they won't look like
island devils if they're
acting like overgrown kids.
You guys. I swear you've never
tasted anything like this!
[CLOWN 87A] Hi, little fella.
Got some tasty candy for ya.
Wanna try it?
It's real good.
Sharp suit there, bud.
Are you and your friends
playing gangster?
[SASHA] There's something
delicious off yonder!
[CONNY] What if that's
the thing Nicolo mentioned?
[JEAN]
Hey! Three more, please!
Sure thing.
[MIKASA] Eren.
You really need to taste this.
It's ice cream, right?
[MIKASA]
Uh-- You know about it?
I think I saw it somewhere
in Dad's memories.
Eldians in the internment zones
usually can't get it.
The outside world's massive,
but they don't want us
to be part of it.
[MIKASA] We didn't
recognize it at the time.
Or maybe we refused to
let ourselves accept it.
[LEVI] Hey! I don't think
that purse belongs to you,
does it, kid?
[RAMZI gasps]
Huh? [Gasps]
[CIVILIAN 87A]
Thief!
Well, look at that.
Another enemy immigrant!
[CIVILIAN 87C]
How'd you get into Marley?
[CIVILIAN 87D]
Bet he stowed away on a ship!
[CIVILIAN 87E]
He can't understand us, can he?
[CIVILIAN 87A]
We could toss him into the sea!
[CIVILIAN 87C]
Nah. I say we smash his hands.
That oughta stop him
from picking pockets.
[CIVILIAN 87E] Why don't we
string the little rat up
somewhere everyone can see him?
It'll scare off the next thief!
There's no need!
Don't hurt him, okay?
I got my purse back,
so why go that far?
Young lady, this is about
more than just your purse.
All us merchants
working in this port
are trying to make
an honest living.
We can't allow the riffraff
to run around
stealing from our customers!
On top of that, this kid
could be a Subject of Ymir.
[SASHA gasps]
[CIVILIAN 87F] Blood testing has
been picking up like crazy
all over during
the past few years.
Now that we know
the devils have been
blending in with the rest of us,
people are losing sleep over it!
[CIVILIAN 87H] Hey! What do
you think you're doing?
[LEVI] I never said
he was a pickpocket.
All I said was the purse
didn't belong to him.
He owes his big sister an
apology for this little prank.
[SASHA gasps]
Jeez. That's children for ya!
But what can ya do? Right?
It's a family thing!
Huh? Oh! Yeah!
I'm sorry my little brother
acted like an idiot, everybody!
Smells like bullshit.
You think we're stupid?
Run for it!
[CIVILIAN 87I]
Hey! Come back!
[ALL panting]
Did anyone see where
the brat ran off to?
Oh. He's right there.
[LEVI gasps]
[LEVI]
Well, then.
So much for the
Azumabito's pocket change.
[KIYOMI] I'm sorry you
had to go through that.
With improvements in
blood testing technology,
countries are beginning to
discover that Subjects of Ymir
have been able to sneak out
of the internment zones
and blend into
the wider population.
The bloodline of Ymir
made its way
across Eldian territory
when the empire was
at the height of its power,
and for many centuries,
the ability to
trace one's lineage
back to a Subject of Ymir
served as proof of noble status
among the global elite.
But as the Empire crumbled,
the aristocrats who'd
been aligned with Eldia
quickly found themselves exiled.
Today, you witnessed
the way Eldians are
typically treated
beyond the walls.
In light of that,
I'm sure you can see
how difficult it will be
to convince the world
to engage with the people of
Paradis on friendly terms.
[ARMIN]
Even so.
If we give up on pursuing
peace at this point,
our only remaining option
will be to throw in
with Zeke and his conspiracy.
We would be leaving
our fates entirely up to him
and sacrificing Historia's life,
and the lives of her children.
That's right.
We're looking for a way
to avoid such a future,
and our search
brought us to Marley.
This "Subject of Ymir
Protection Group"
will be debuting at the
international forum tomorrow.
They may be able to help.
[KIYOMI]
It's possible.
Though I would caution
against assuming
your goals and theirs
are in alignment.
[HANGE] We're not,
and we won't make contact
until we've had a chance
to observe them.
If they show promise,
and if they'll agree to
hold a meeting with us,
they can help us get our
message out into the world.
You've come to
make it known that
the people of Paradis
wish to coexist in peace?
[HANGE]
Yes.
[KIYOMI] Rest assured,
the Azumabito clan will
happily aid you
in pursuing said goal.
But... I must wonder
how realistic you've been
in assessing
your odds of success.
[HANGE gasps]
Fact is, chances are slim
even if we do everything right.
And we'll be in constant danger.
But still, we at least
have to try.
As long as there's a chance,
it's our duty to take it.
Far be it from me
to tell you otherwise.
[Gasps]
[MIKASA gasps]
Wait a minute. Where's Eren?
[MIKASA panting]
[MIKASA]
Eren!
What are you thinking?
Did you forget we're
undercover in enemy territory
and you're their
number one target?
Everyone's been
out looking for you.
Is that the boy from the market?
Did something happen here?
No, nothing yet.
[MIKASA]
What does that mean? Is this--
[EREN]
These people are refugees who
lost their homes
in Marley's wars.
They're like us.
The world they knew
before suddenly ended.
Everything they had was taken.
And the freedom they
enjoyed is long gone.
Mikasa. I need to ask you
why you care for me
as much as you do.
[Gasps]
Because I saved you?
Back when we were little kids?
Or is it more 'cause you
see me as family?
[Gasps]
Mikasa. What am I to you?
Well...
Y-You're my, uh...
You're my family.
[MIKASA gasps]
[Speaking a foreign language]
What?
I think that was an invitation.
[ARMIN]
Hey!
What the hell do you think
you're doing, you maniac?
[CONNY]
You some kinda moron?
Perfect timing.
[RAMZI'S GRANDPA chuckles]
Ahh.
[RAMZI'S GRANDPA laughs]
[BOTH gasp]
Ladies and gentlemen,
this new organization
advocates for
the Subjects of Ymir living as
refugees around the globe!
These desperate people
are not responsible
for the crimes of
the Eldian Empire,
but rather,
its most tragic victims.
The living legacy of
its effort to corrupt
all the peoples of the world
with Eldian blood!
The taint of Eldia is all but
cleansed from the earth.
There's only one corner
where it continues to fester:
the island of Paradis,
where the empire's
most loyal subjects fled
in the wake of Marley's victory
a hundred years ago.
It is the island devils alone
who pose a true
threat to humanity!
[Gasps]
[MIKASA] That was the day
when Eren truly left us.
Later on, he would
send us a letter.
He said he was going to
leave our futures up to Zeke.
By the next time we saw him,
it was too late.
Looking back,
I still don't know if
there was some better way.
Maybe everything had
already been decided
from the start.
But I can't help wondering.
When he asked me
that question...
...what if I'd given him
a different answer?
[MIKASA] Would we still be
in this situation right now?
[EREN]
Where did all of it begin?
Was it there?
[EREN]
No. It doesn't matter where.
[EREN] Everything happened
as I willed it.
Everything begins here.
Eren. There's only one way
to break the cycle of violence
for Eldia and the world.
You must support
the euthanization plan.
The brass won't be an obstacle.
They've been
happily sipping away
at that wine we tainted
with spinal fluid.
You're a part of Zeke's plan
because he believes in you.
Please return his faith.
[EREN] For now, I'll pretend
to go along with Zeke's plot.
You need to do the same.
Keep your head down for a while.
So we play along
with him for now,
but what happens after that?
[EREN] The MPs are still
pushing the same idea.
They wanna turn you into a Titan
and have you eat Zeke.
They're not gonna be
talked out of it.
You can either fight or flee.
[HISTORIA]
Since I came out here,
I've had more to think about
than just raising cattle.
I know what they're planning,
but running and fighting
aren't my only options.
If making me a Titan gives us
the best chance of
saving the island,
then I'm prepared to do it.
Realistically,
it's the only way.
Even so. I'm grateful.
I've got friends who did
everything they could for me.
You all fought hard
to protect me.
[HISTORIA] It's enough
that you tried, I mean it.
Maybe it is enough for you,
but not for me.
[Gasps]
I'll trample it to the ground--
the whole outside world.
And every person in it.
Men, women, children.
Every last one.
That isn't the answer, Eren!
Most of the people out there
don't have anything to do with
what we've gone through!
They would die ignorant
and terrified, like your mom.
You'll be killing
innocent people
for reasons they'll
never get to know!
It's horrible. You're right.
But when I'm done,
we'll finally be able to
break free of the cycle
we've been trapped in
for two thousand years.
Our long history of hate
will be buried in the
ruins of civilization.
The MPs. They plan to
make you bear children
to be sacrificed for the island.
They'll keep forcing children
to eat their parents.
I won't let them.
Eren, please. Don't do it.
I'll have no choice
but to try and stop you.
'Cause if I don't,
I'll have to live with
the world's blood on my hands.
And I can't.
I know it's a burden,
but if you can bear it
till I've got
the Founder's power,
I'll make you forget
you ever knew it was coming.
How could I, though?
I know you can,
'cause you're the person
who saved my life
back in that cavern.
The worst girl who ever lived.
Headaches, huh?
Well. I doubt
there's a connection.
It would have to be
some genetic illness,
but Mister Ksaver and
Marley's researchers
would have made note of that.
Our studies do indicate
the Ackermann bloodline
carries some odd quirks.
Powers that activate when their
survival instincts
are triggered.
But this theory that she's
reflexively guarding her "host"?
To be honest, it seems
a little far-fetched to me.
I think it's far simpler
than you're making it, Eren.
There are straightforward
explanations
for all the behaviors
you're describing
that have nothing to do with
genetics or conditioning.
She doesn't slaughter
Titans out of some
inborn compulsion
to keep you alive.
She does it because
she adores you.
Hey, Eren, listen.
[ZEKE] Well? What do you think
you're going to say to her?
That's not a serious
question, is it?
Even if everything goes right,
I've only got four
more years to live.
What would you think
about me having a child?
[EREN groaning]
My life's end date is set,
but my friends will keep living
long after I'm gone.
[EREN groaning]
[EREN]
And that's what I want.
[EREN groaning]
[EREN]
What I need.
[EREN] For them to live
long, happy lives.
[ADMIRAL 87A]
An allied global fleet.
Nearly all of the largest
guns ever manufactured
have been gathered
from across the globe,
here, today,
off the coast of Marley.
The combined brainpower
of the world's nations
is focused entirely on
resolving this shared crisis.
It took nothing short
of a miracle to even
assemble a fleet
of this magnitude.
And by that miracle alone,
humanity still clings to hope.
[ADMIRAL 87A] For salvation
from this rumbling.
[Gasps]
[ADMIRAL 87A gasps]
[MARLEYAN SOLDIERS gasping]
[Gasps]
[MARLEYAN SOLDIER 87B]
Is that...? Yeah.
It could only be...
the Attack Titan!
[MARLEYAN SOLDIERS gasp]
[EREN]
I'll kill them all.
Every last one.
[EREN]
The world over.